A Guide to the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Officers, RG 3 FA1797
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1931-2017; 1; 12.65 Cubic Feet 35 containers
  - Hills, Lee, 1970-1997; 1.7; 5.51 Cubic Feet 14 letter document boxes and 1 half-box
    - Journalism Program--Stanford University John S. Knight Fellowship Program, 1987 July 18 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Progress report on the John S. Knight Fellowship Program by the president of Stanford University.
    - Journalism Program--Stanford University John S. Knight Fellowship Program, 1988 May 6-July 1 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 644
      Progress report on the John S. Knight Fellowship Program by James Risser, director of the program, and Lee Hills correspondence and notes on the program.
    - Journalism Program--Stanford University John S. Knight Fellowship Program, 1989 May 11-August 29 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 645
      Progress report on the John S. Knight Fellowship Program by James Risser, director of the program, list of seminars for the 1988-89 academic year, and correspondence with Lee Hills.
    - Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics, 1989 August 10-October 16 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 646
      Lee Hills' notes on his interviews with candidates for the Commission, including Dick Schultz and Al Witte, Edward Foote, Hanna Gray, David Roselle, Lamar Alexander, Bob Andringa, William Muse, Jim Whalen, Jeffrey Orleans, and Mike Schwartz.
    - Knight, James L.--Estate, 1991 February 12-1992 March 24 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 647
      Memos and correspondence re: Estate of James L. Knight, and issues relating to the donation of 75.5% of the estate to the Knight Foundation.
    - Knight, John S.-- Concerns about the location of Knight Foundation, 1979 November 13-1989 February 10 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 648
      Letters from John S. Knight to his attorney, Norman Sugarman, and C.C. Gibson re: his concern over the foundation remaining in Akron after his death. Also included are a response by Sugarman to Mr. Knight's query about legal action to keep the foundation in Akron, and letters by C.C. Gibson to Rolfe Neill and Creed Black to accompany this "evidence" to back his argument to keep the foundation in Akron as per Jack Knight's wishes.
    - Knight, John S.-- Book on, 1980 July 25-1984 November 26 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 649
      Correspondence re: the writing of a biography on John S. Knight. Charles Whited was the author finally contracted to write the biography of Knight after his death.
    - Knight, John S.-- Estate, 1981 June 20-1990 December 28 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 650
      Briefing on John S. Knight Estate and Knight Foundation from meeting on 6/20/81; report on plan for the John S. Knight Estate, including plans for the Foundation; 12/8/81 report on the impact of JSK's estate on the Foundation, Lee Hills' notes on questions to ask Norman Sugarman, and memos re: stock transactions between the estate of John S. Knight and Knight Foundation.
    - Knight, John S.-- Memorials, 1981 June 26-1982 March 9 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 651
      Correspondence re: possible memorials to John S. Knight.
    - Legal Issues, general, 1974 January 17-1983 June 6 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 652
      Correspondence re: legal relationship between Foundation and Knight Newspapers, guidelines for Ohio private foundations, sale of Foundation's stocks to Knight-Ridder, business holdings.
    - Legal Issues, Knight-Ridder, 1989 April 24-1992 March 9 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      Knight File Number - 653
      Correspondence re: the legal separateness of Knight Foundation from Knight-Ridder, and the confusion therein.
    - Literacy, 1975 February 28 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      Knight File Number - 654
      Correspondence re: the possibility of Knight Foundation funding a literacy project.
    - Literacy--John S. Knight Writing Program at Cornell University, 1986 June 26-1987 April 16 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      Knight File Number - 655
      Proposal and correspondence re: the progress of the John S. Knight Writing Program at Cornell University to prevent illiteracy.
    - Maidenburg, Ben, 1972 October 31-1978 April 26 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      Knight File Number - 656
      Correspondence re: Ben Maidenburg's illness and retirement as president of Knight Foundation.
    - Miami--Foundation's move to, 1989 December 19-1990 March 20 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      Knight File Number - 657
      Memo from James L. Knight supporting a move of the Foundation from Akron to Miami; Lee Hills' notes on the subject.
    - Offices--Akron, 1974 February 5-1980 December 10 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      Knight File Number - 658
      Correspondence re: moving operations of the Foundation from an office at the Akron Beacon Journal to its own space rented in the Cascade Building.
    - Personnel Issues, 1982 January 4-1992 February 20 (Box 10, Folder 19)
      Knight File Number - 659
      Correspondence re: staff enlargement, personnel policy, retirement plan for the future, salary of chief financial officer.
    - Planning, 1972 August 22 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 660
      Lee Hills' memo on "A Working Paper on the Future of the Knight Foundation," which includes his ideas for planning to be discussed at Board of Trustees meeting of 9/20/72. Issues discussed include diversification of the portfolio, spending guidelines, and kinds of programs for the Foundation to develop.
    - Planning, 1981 March 17 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 661
      Lee Hills memo re: future requests for grants in light of Reagan Administration's cuts in government spending on arts and education.
    - Planning Review Committee, 1995 February 17 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 662
      Memo on questions and issues to address on Board of Trustees retreat, re: planning.
    - Policy--"White Paper", 1978 January 5-1980 January 25 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 663
      "White Paper" discussing Knight Foundation policies; draft by C.C. Gibson, comments and reactions by officers.
    - Policy, 1981 June 22-August 6 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 664
      Policy concepts for the consideration of the Trustees of Knight Foundation, and memos related to preparing stated policies on programs, finances and investments.
    - Policy, 1982 December 2 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 665
      Memo on permissable activities of Trustees during political campaigns.
    - Policy, 1986 December 16-1989 June 13 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 666
      Memos re: unofficial policy against grants for radio and television projects.
    - Policy "Endowment grants", 1987 May 12-October 1 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 667
      Memos discussing the creation of a policy on Endowment grants.
    - Policy, 1989 November 2-1991 September 18 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 668
      Conflict of Interest Policy, resolution and Disclosure Questionnaire (1989); Draft of Conflict of Interest Policy Regarding Transactions Between the Foundation and its Officers or Trustees, or Transactions Which Affect the Corporation; amended policy as adopted in September 1991.
    - Presidential Replacement Search, 1979 November 13-1989 October 10 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 669
      Correspondence and minutes of Nominating Committee meetings re: finding a new president for Knight Foundation upon C.C. Gibson's retirement. Issues discussed include moving the foundation out of Akron. Also included are a position description, and biographies and resumes of job candidates.
    - Professional Organizations, 1976 May 17-1988 July 1 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 670
      Correspondence re: issues raised in professional organizations such as the Council on Foundations, the Americas Foundation, Conference on Terrorism and the Media, Media and the Law Conference, the Ohio Foundation Conference, Independent Sector.
    - Programs--Arts and Culture, 1992, 1992 August 5-6 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 671
      Memos from Penny McPhee re: Meeting with American Federation of Arts/Collection Sharing Program, and Report on United Arts Fund Conference in Seattle.
    - Programs--Arts and Culture, 1994, 1994 May 1 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      Knight File Number - 672
      "Feasibililty Study for a Museum Art Loan Program," prepared for the Knight Foundation by Strategic Grantmaker Services. Gary Burger and Dr. Thomas Wolf authored the study.
    - Programs--Cities, 1986 April 1-October 8 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      Knight File Number - 673
      Lee Hills' notes on and comments to Cities Program Associates. Includes his notes to Knight-Ridder Newspaper Management Conference in 1986, memos to individual associates regarding grants to their cities, letter re: relationship of Knight Foundation to grantseekers in Miami upon the Foundation's move to Miami, memo on role of Associates, notes on Workshop for Associates.
    - Programs--Cities, 1987 May 14 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      Knight File Number - 674
      Origins and overview of Cities Program, handwritten by C.C. Gibson.
    - Programs--Cities, 1988 March 24 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      Knight File Number - 675
      Memo to Planning Committee re: Possible Guidelines for Associates in the Knight Foundation Cities Program.
    - Programs--Cities, 1988 May 1-September 14 (Box 11, Folder 17)
      Knight File Number - 676
      Memos re: Proposal review procedures of Foundation Associates.
    - Programs--Community Initiatives, 1991 October 20-December 16 (Box 11, Folder 18)
      Knight File Number - 677
      Correspondence and notes re: target areas for program, list of associates, Jill Conway's comments on program priorities for Community Initiatives, change of name of Cities Program to Community Initiatives Program, change of name of Associates to Advisors.
    - Programs--Community Initiatives, 1992, 1992 January 16-August 20 (Box 11, Folder 19)
      Knight File Number - 678
      Correspondence re: Kids Voting program, Community Initiatives Advisory Committee notes and President's report from March, 1992 board meeting, Advisory Committee Guidelines, list of members of Community Initiatives Advisory Committee.
    - Program Planning Issues, 1986 May 5 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 679
      Memo and reference material on future discussions on literacy and opening grants to public universities.
    - Publications--Foundation Directories, 1976 November 17 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 681
      Correspondence re: Knight Foundation's listing in Taft Corporation's directory of foundations. The final listing is included.
    - Publicity, 1989 February 7-1994 February 11 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 682
      Memos on press coverage of Knight Foundation activities, discussion of need for Communications Director, Lee Hills' article on publicizing foundation activities from The Foundation News.
    - Student Loan Program, 1982 May 26 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 683
      Memo from C.C. Gibson to Board of Trustees re: plans to collect on outstanding student loans.
    - Study Committee re: Knight Foundation Reorganization, 1986 October 6-December 8 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 684
      Correspondence from Trustees re: work of a study committee to discuss the reorganization of the governance of the Foundation. Issues include size of board, length of term of trustees, background and experience, geographic areas, committees and compensation, and matters of the administration and staff of the Foundation.
    - Trustees--Batten, James K., 1995 September 12 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 685
      Request from Davidson College for grant to create a memorial scholarship and professorship in honor of Jim Batten, and resolution by Board of Trustees.
    - Trustees--Toomey, Barbara Knight, 1980 February 20-1994 February 22 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 686
      Memos on her selection as Board of Trustees member in 1980, and her resignation in 1993.
    - Trustees--Meetings: Agenda Items for Review, 1971 March 5-July 21 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 689
      Writeups for grant requests for review at Board of Trustees meetings of 3/5/71, 3/20/75, and 7/21/75.
    - Trustees--Meetings: Agenda Items for Review, 1976 March 25-December 20 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 690
      Writeups for grant requests for review at Board of Trustees meetings of 3/25/76, 6/21/76, 9/29/76, 12/20/76.
    - Trustees--Meetings: Agenda Items for Review, 1977 March 22-December 16 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 691
      Writeups for grant requests for review at Board of Trustees meetings of 3/22/77, 9/21/77, and 12/16/77.
    - Trustees--Meetings: Agenda Items for Review, 1978 March 22-June 20 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 692
      Writeups for grant requests for review at Board of Trustees meetings of 3/22/78, and 6/20/78.
    - Trustees--Meetings: Agenda Items for Review, 1979 December 14 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 693
      Writeups for grant requests for review at Board of Trustees meeting of 12/14/79.
    - Trustees--Meetings: Agenda Items for Review, 1980 March-December (Box 12, Folder 13-16)
      Knight File Number - 694
      Writeups for grant requests for review at Board of Trustees meetings of 3/80, 6/80, 9/80, and 12/80. 4 file folders.
    - Trustees--Meetings: Agenda Items for Review, 1981 March 31-December 31 (Box 13, Folder 1-4)
      Knight File Number - 695
      Writeups for grant requests for review at Board of Trustees meetings of 3/81, 6/81, 9/81, and 12/81. 4 file folders.
    - Trustees--Meetings: Agenda Items for Review, 1982 March 31-December 31 (Box 13, Folder 5-8)
      Knight File Number - 696
      Writeups for grant requests for review at Board of Trustees meetings of 3/82, 6/82, 9/82, and 12/82. 4 file folders.
    - Trustees--Meetings: Agenda Items for Review, 1983 March 31-December 31 (Box 13, Folder 9-12)
      Knight File Number - 697
      Writeups for grant requests for review at Board of Trustees meetings of 3/83, 6/83, 9/83, and 12/83. 4 file folders.
    - Trustees--Meetings: Agenda Items for Review, 1984 June 30-December 31 (Box 14, Folder 1-3)
      Knight File Number - 698
      Writeups for grant requests for review at Board of Trustees meetings of 6/84, 9/84, and 12/84. 3 file folders.
    - Trustees--Meetings: Agenda Items for Review, 1985 March 31-December 31 (Box 14, Folder 5-7)
      Knight File Number - 699
      Writeups for grant requests for review at Board of Trustees meetings of 3/85, 6/85, 9/85, and 12/85. 4 file folders.
    - Trustees--Meetings: Agenda Items for Review, 1986 March 31-September 30 (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
      Knight File Number - 700
      Writeups for grant requests for review at Board of Trustees meetings of 3/86 and 9/86. 2 file folders.
    - Trustees--Meeting Notes, 1976 December 21-1991 June 20 (Box 14, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 701
      Lee Hills' typed notes on issues discussed at Board of Trustee meetings. Issues include effect of John S. Knight's death on the financial situation of Knight Foundation, effect of influx of Cuban exiles on the Miami community and what the Knight Foundation can do to help; planning for an increased staff and grantmaking capabilities upon receipt of stock from John S. Knight's estate; governance of Knight Foundation.
    - Trustees--Meeting Topics, 1980 February 4-1991 June 7 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 702
      Correspondence re: comments of Trustees on the topics they feel should be discussed at board meetings. Topics include guidelines for Trustees, geographic location of the Foundation, ultimate dissolution of the Foundation, future composition of the board, should Knight Foundation limit grants to responses to appeals, Trustees' meetings, areas of interest, internal guidelines for operating procedures, investment of funds, and miscellaneous.
    - Trustees--Meetings, Special, 1993 November 29-December 13 (Box 14, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 703
      Memo and supplemental report to the Trustees regarding the Foundation's proposed reincorporation in Florida.
    - Trustees--Memo re: Conflicts of Interest, 1982 January 6 (Box 14, Folder 13)
      Knight File Number - 704
      Memo and reference article to inform Trustees of Congress' concern about conflicts of interest within Foundation activities.
    - Trustees--Memos re: Makeup of the Board, 1986 January 1-1991 April 16 (Box 14, Folder 14)
      Knight File Number - 705
      Correspondence re: makeup of the Board of Trustees, list of board members from 1950-1991, Barbara Toomey's and Rolfe Neill's thoughts on board composition, ages of board members as of 1/20/91, resume of Marjorie Knight Crane.
    - Trustees--Operating Procedure, 1986 November 14 (Box 14, Folder 15)
      Knight File Number - 706
      Memo from C.C. Gibson to Trustees discussing operating procedure for telephone grant requests.
    - Trustees--Salaries and Pension Plan, 1982 July 26-1991 December 12 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      Knight File Number - 707
      Correspondence discussing and comparing the salaries, fees and pension plans of Knight Foundation trustees and committee members vs. that of other foundations.
    - Committees-Nominating, Meeting Minutes, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Committees-Nominating, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 505
      Notes on Composition of Board, containing quotes from James L. Knight, and Norman Sugarman about whom should be on the KF board.
    - Committees-Nominating, 1987 March 17-19 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 507
      Meeting minutes of the Nominating Committee.
    - Committees-Nominating, 1987 April 16 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 508
      Orientation materials for new board members (Rolfe Neill, Beverly Knight Olson, James K. Batten and W. Gerald Austen), including biographies of the above, overview of stipends, fees for board members.
    - Committees-Nominating, 1988 February 15 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 509
      Meeting Minutes of Nominating Committee.
    - Committees-Nominating, 1991 January 6-April 5 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 510
      Correspondence re: search for new trustees (Larry Jinks).
    - Committees-Nominating, 1992 February 17 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 511
    - Finance, 1987 March 3-1988 August 12 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 558
      Correspondence relating to IRS audit concerning salary of Charles Clark and John S. Knight biography.
    - Board of Trustees/Governance Issues, 1991 April 30-June 20 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 983
      Lee Hills' notes on conversations with Barbara Toomey regarding issues of governance, including family representation on the board.
    - Move to Miami, 1989 January 1-1990 December 31 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 985
      Correspondence regarding the move of the Knight Foundation from Akron, OH to Miami, FL.
    - Legal Issues: Community Advisors, 1974 November 4-1978 February 24 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 2491
      Correspondence to newspaper executives in Knight-Ridder cities re: advising Knight Foundation on grants in their cities. Includes grant policy and statement of information sent to newspaper executives.
    - Tax Laws, 1997 August 12 (Box 15, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 2492
      Tax Laws re: conduct of affairs of Knight Foundation; guidelines prepared by Norman Sugarman.
    - Detroit Institute of Arts, c. 1987 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      Knight File Number - 5915
      Note from Henry Ford II to Lee Hills thanking Hills for his work at the DIA. Note, and museum pamphlet, were found in a book given to Alberto Ibarguen.
  - Ibarguen, Alberto, 2006-2017; 1.8; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
    - Executive Committee Notes and Materials, 2012 October 14-2014 December 14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 5113
      Conditions Governing Access
      Restricted - Open 2025
      Notes compiled by Lilly Weinberg, special assistant to Alberto, re: executive committee actions. Also included are notes on Executive Committee/CEP action items, Fluxx Implementation schedule (a new grant tracking software), and the launch of Connect2Compete, part of the Universal Access initiative. Also included are background materials for the October 2, 2013 Executive Committee meeting: Community Information Leadership Partnerships, KCIC Potential Deep Dive Partners, and a Media Learning Seminar Concept Memo, agendas for the October 29th All Day Strategy Session, December 10th Full Staff Meeting, launch of search for Mayur Patel's replacement, and Media Learning Seminar takeaways. Also included are due dates for Q4 and 2015 Board materials, and CEP discussion points.
    - Correspondence and Memos, 2007 March 24-2016 December 22 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 4065
      Restricted - Open 2027
      Emails from Alberto Ibarguen to staff re: transformational grant-making, budget and going forward into 2009 at KF (in response to the drop in the endowment due to adverse economic conditions); Knight naming instructions from Trustees; the Knight Commission and the FCC; KF being named Good Magazine top 30 companies to work for; KF's announcement that it would fund the completion of Biloxi's Ohr-Okeefe Museum; confidential memo from Belinda Lawrence re: Clara Knight distinction through the organization Women of Tomorrow; reaction to the announcement of 2011 Knight News Challenge winners; launch of the Tow-Knight Center for Entrepreneurial Journalism; Knight Arts Challenge/Philadelphia; the Digital Library race; the 4th Media Learning Seminar; a letter from Jim Bailey, Cambridge Associates, re: terms of modification to the contract for financial management services which should result in a fee reduction; a memo to KF trustees re: staff grant making authority, which outlines the delegation of authority on small grant-making to vice presidents and program directors and a memo from Alberto to Marjorie Crane and Beverly Olson (copy to Rob Briggs) re: Knight Plaza at Museum Park, Miami. Olson and Briggs' replies are included. Also included are memos re: The Coming Year; responses to questions re: KF and journalism funding; KF's grant to help save Detroit Institute of Arts from being forced to sell its art to pay bankrupt Detroit's debts. Trustee responses are included. Also, announcement of KF being awarded the Edward R. Murrow prize by Washington State University; emails to staff re: large number of staff attending board meetings and board announcement re: IRS approval of KF grant-making to individuals; Detroit Bankruptcy settlement announcement; KF recognition by ProPublica at Online News Association awards ceremony; a Thanksgiving message; memo from Eric Newton re: the origin of the John S. Knight quote used by KF on its website and other publications: "Thus we seek to bestir the people..."; memo re: upgrades to the KF financial systems, including financial reporting, budgeting, payment processing and expense reimbursement; staff changes at Knight in 2015; his annual Thanksgiving message to the staff and trustees; "selfies" with Eric Newton at the Reporters Committee award presentation and the announcement of the Knight First Amendment Institute at Columbia University; invitation to staff to participate in a Black Lives in America discussion with Trabian Shorters, July 2016; Inside Philanthropy article by David Callahan, "The Futurist: Alberto Ibarguen and the Remaking of the Knight Foundation" re: Alberto's leadership as KF continues its creative and experimental grantmaking activities. In a memo to staff and trustees dated December 22, 2016, Alberto took issue with several conclusions cited in the article, especially the "competitive male vibe" at the office.